YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 10. Audiovisual Materials
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES II. VIDEOTAPES
  - Videotapes-Originals DO NOT USE, [see boxes 1111 and 1112 for Use Copies]
    - Dorothy I. Height Tribute Dinner sponsored by YWCA and National Council of Negro Women, Plaza Hotel, New York City, 5 Nov 1986
      - "The Height of Dedication" a multimedia salute presented at the dinner
        - Raw footage, MBR 20s, 20XBR (3 tapes) (Box 1075, Folder 12-14)
        - VHS Master (Box 1075, Folder 15)
      - Dinner footage, VHS, UCA 20s (3 tapes) (Box 1075, Folder 16-18)
    - "It's Okay to Say No Way!" Teen Pregnancy Prevention Program music video, 1986 (Box 1076)
      - Master VHS * (Box 1076, Folder 1)
      - New Credits, UCA 20s (Box 1076, Folder 2)
      - Interview re "It's Okay... " with Suzan Flanaga, Executive Director of Shreveport YWCA on KTAL-TV (Arkansas-Louisiana-Texas Today Show), BCA 10, 1986 (Box 1076, Folder 3)
      - Piece re "It's Okay... " on "Black News" YNYW, Channel 5, Fox network stations, 17 May 1986 - Umatic (Box 1076, Folder 4)
    - Tribute to Women in International Industry (TWIN) ceremony, Copley Plaza Hotel, Boston, Jun 1986, VHS (Box 1076, Folder 5)
    - Convention Preparation Meetings?, 14-15 Jul 1986
      - National Support, Discussion #7: Gwendolyn Baker, Skip Dockstader, Anita S., Lynn J., Gerri S., Umatic, 14 Jul 1986 (Box 1076, Folder 6)
      - "Gwendolyn Baker: Convention, Discussion Intro," VHS,14-15 Jul (Box 1076, Folder 7)
    - "The National Support Plan for Community Associations," VHS, Aug 1986 * (Box 1076, Folder 8)
    - Learning Center XX, Executive Management, VHS, Oct 1986 * (Box 1076, Folder 9)
    - "Women Who Care," VHS, 19 Nov 1986 (Box 1076, Folder 10)
    - Soviet Women's Committee exchange trips
      - "Russia" [discussion of the visit to the USSR], VHS, n.d. (Box 1076, Folder 11)
      - Moscow with Peter Jennings, VHS, Feb 1986 [appears to be taped newscasts, ABC News] (Box 1076, Folder 12)
      - "Dr. Gwendolyn C. Baker: Trip to Russia, Tape 3," UCA 20s (Box 1076, Folder 13)
      - Women's Dialogue, USSR, VHS, n.d. * (Box 1076, Folder 14)
    - "Nightwatch" Dr. Baker Interview, CBS-TV, VHS, 1986 (Box 1076, Folder 15)
    - Racial Justice Program, "Let Freedom Ring in South Africa," VHS, 16 Jan 1987 (Box 1076, Folder 16)
    - "Probing PR," workshop with Sunshine Overkamp, Feb 1987, VHS * (Box 1076, Folder 17)
    - Mary Wolf Meditation Room Sculpture Dedication, National Board Meeting, Umatic, Master footage and edited master, Feb 1987 (Box 1076, Folder 18-19)
    - "Shirley Devin, Agape ISO," Umatic, 14 Feb 1987 (Box 1076, Folder 20)
    - Corporate Responsibility of the President and Executive Director, presentation by Glendora Putnam, 18 Mar 1987, VHS (Box 1076, Folder 21)
    - "Inside the Soviet Union with Helen Graham, V.P. National Board YWCA," "Sounding" channel 4, Detroit, MI, talk show, Umatic, 21 Mar 1987 (Box 1077, Folder 1)
    - Young Women's Employment Training Project
      - Edited master, 26 Apr 1987, Umatic and VHS * (Box 1077, Folder 2-3)
      - Raw footage, tapes A-C, E-M, UCA 20s (Box 1077, Folder 4-16)
    - Gwendolyn Calvert Baker in Turkey: videotransfer of photo prints, Umatic and VHS, May 1987 (Box 1078, Folder 1-2)
    - "Y-Zine Magazine," Umatic (2 copies), May 1987 (Box 1078, Folder 3-4)
    - "Racial Justice I and The MAY Show, ISO tape #2," Umatic, 30 May 1987 (Box 1078, Folder 5)
    - The MAY Show: The Board and Staff Talent Show, Umatic (3 tapes) and VHS (2 tapes), 30 May 1987 (Box 1078, Folder 6-10)
    - Hearing on "Child Care Services for Job Corps," Panel 1, 23 Jul 1987, VHS * (Box 1078, Folder 11)
    - World Council, Phoenix, Arizona, 25 Aug-5 Sep 1987
      - Pre-Council meetings for young women on Development with Justice, 22-24 Aug, Umatic (Box 1078, Folder 12-13)
      - Orientation for New World Council Delegates, Umatic (Box 1078, Folder 14)
      - World Council Review (featuring LDC Peace Site Dedication), Umatic and VHS * (Box 1078, Folder 15-16)
      - Peace Site Dedication, Leadership Development Center, VHS * (Box 1078, Folder 17)
      - Introduction to the candidates for World Council President, Umatic (Box 1078, Folder 18)
      - "A Salute to a Leader: Ann Northcote," President of the World YWCA, 1983-87, Umatic (Box 1079, Folder 1)
      - "The Past Is Prologue: Historical Review of the YWCA of the USA," a 6-projector multi-image slide program transferred to video, produced for World Council meeting, 1987 (Box 1079)
        - Umatic (8/87 version) (Box 1079, Folder 2-3)
        - Umatic (10/87 version) and VHS (Box 1079, Folder 4-5)
      - First edit, Beta (Box 1079, Folder 6)
      - Interviews, Umatic (Box 1079, Folder 7-8)
      - Interviews, President, raw footage, n.d., Umatic (Box 1079, Folder 9)
      - Interviews, B. Rami, USSR (Box 1079, Folder 10)
      - Logo, Umatic (Box 1079, Folder 11)
      - Narration, Umatic (Box 1079, Folder 12-14)
      - Script, narrator: M.J., Umatic (Box 1079, Folder 15)
      - Jewel Graham, Umatic (Box 1079, Folder 16)
      - 25 Aug: Morning Session, Umatic (Box 1080, Folder 1-3)
      - 27 Aug
        - Keynote speaker: Ann Maria Tepedino, Umatic (Box 1080, Folder 4-5)
        - Workshop: Lobbying, Central America, Umatic (Box 1080, Folder 6)
      - 28 Aug: Southern Africa, Umatic (Box 1080, Folder 8-11)
      - 31 Aug: Dame Nita Barrow, Umatic (Box 1080, Folder 12)
      - 1 Sep: Banners, Umatic (Box 1080, Folder 13)
      - 2 Sep: Afternoon speaker, "Youth Employ II," Umatic (Box 1080, Folder 14)
      - 3 Sep: Plenary Session, Umatic
        - Tapes 1 and 2 (Box 1080, Folder 15-16)
        - Tapes 3 and 4 (Box 1081, Folder 1-2)
      - 5 Sep: Afternoon Session, Umatic (Box 1081, Folder 3)
    - KBUR TV, Duluth, MN, Public Service Announcements for the YWCA, 27 Aug 1987, VHS (Box 1081, Folder 3a)
    - JobPlus: A Job Opportunity Partnership Program, Dayton, Ohio YWCA, VHS, Nov 1987 * (Box 1081, Folder 4)
    - Learning Center XXI: Racial Justice, Umatic, 13 Nov 1987 (Box 1081, Folder 5-8)
    - "Follow Your Dream," YWCA of the U.S.A./Arizona Department of Education vocational education video, 1988
      - VHS (Box 1081, Folder 9)
      - MBR 20s Dub (Box 1081, Folder 10)
      - Freeway Dance segments, filmed 11/87, Umatic (Box 1081, Folder 11)
    - "Making a Difference," YWCA Membership Video, Umatic and VHS, 1988 (Box 1081, Folder 12-13)
    - Palestine Refugees: Travels of Glendora Putman, slide transfer, Umatic, 1988 (Box 1081, Folder 14)
    - 3 Public Service Announcements "YWCA: Women as Winners," "YWCA: Homeless," and "YWCA: Child Care," plus 7 logo tags, Umatic, and VHS, 1988 (Box 1081, Folder 15-16)
    - "Women Candidates in the Age of Television," Institute for Public Leadership, VHS, 1988 (Box 1081, Folder 17)
    - YWCA Animated Logos, VHS, 1988 (Box 1081, Folder 18)
    - YWCA Old Logo, Umatic, 1988 (Box 1081, Folder 19)
    - Peer Approach Counseling by Teens (P.A.C.T.), Umatic, 11-12 Jan 1988
      - Role Playing, 11 Jan 1988, morning session (Box 1082, Folder 1)
      - Abortion, 11 Jan 1988, afternoon session (Box 1082, Folder 2)
      - Child Abuse, 12 Jan 1988 (Box 1082, Folder 3-4)
      - Community Meeting, 12 Jan 1988 (Box 1082, Folder 5)
    - "The YWCA Story," Commorato Video Productions, Fort Wayne, Indiana, Umatic, 2 Feb 1988 (Box 1082, Folder 6)
    - Convention Planning Meeting presentation, Umatic, VHS, Mar 1988 * (Box 1082, Folder 7-8)
    - "The YWCA as a Single Sex Organization," Umatic, VHS, Mar 1988 * (Box 1082, Folder 9-10)
    - Institute for Public Leadership, Apr 1988
      - Opening Session, Umatic, 15 Apr (Box 1082, Folder 11-12)
      - Health care and housing, Umatic, 15 Apr (Box 1082, Folder 13-14)
      - Speaker: Erma Henderson, President of Detroit City Council, Umatic, 16 Apr (Box 1082, Folder 15)
      - Issue Reports, Umatic, 17 Apr (Box 1082, Folder 16-18)
    - YWCA Logo, VHS, 11 May 1988 (Box 1083, Folder 1)
    - YWCA Retirement Fund, Inc.: "Growing Together," Umatic and VHS, Jun 1988 (Box 1083, Folder 2-3)
    - 31st National Convention, 22-26 Jun 1988
      - Slate, Past is Prologue, Opening and closing, Umatic and VHS (Box 1083, Folder 4-5)
      - Wednesday, 22 Jun
        - Raw footage, Noon Session and reception, Umatic (Box 1083, Folder 6-15)
        - Raw footage, Reception and afternoon session, Umatic (10 tapes) (Box 1083, Folder 16-19)
          - Tapes 1-4 (Box 1083, Folder 16-19)
          - Tapes 5-10 (Box 1084, Folder 1-6)
      - Thursday, 23 Jun
        - Keynote address by s Cardenas Ramirez, edited master Umatic and VHS * (Box 1084, Folder 7-8)
        - Raw footage, plenary, workshops, and training, Umatic (Box 1084, Folder 9-17)
        - Raw footage, World Night, Umatic (9 tapes)
          - Tapes 1 and 2 (Box 1084, Folder 18-19)
          - Tapes 3 to 9 (Box 1085, Folder 1-7)
      - Thursday 23 Jun and Friday, 24 Jun: raw footage, World Night (cont'd) and Active Americans, Umatic (Box 1085, Folder 8)
      - Friday, 24 Jun
        - Raw footage, morning session, Umatic (Box 1085, Folder 9-16)
        - Raw footage, Racial Justice Awards Luncheon (?), Umatic
          - Tapes 1-4 (Box 1085, Folder 17-20)
          - Tapes 5-6 (Box 1086, Folder 1-2)
        - Raw footage, afternoon, Umatic (Box 1086, Folder 3-10)
        - Raw footage, miscellaneous, Umatic (Box 1086, Folder 11-13)
      - Friday, 24 Jun and Saturday, 25 Jun: raw footage, YWCA polling place and morning plenary, Umatic (Box 1086, Folder 13)
      - Saturday, 25 Jun
        - Raw footage, morning plenary, Umatic (13 tapes)
          - Tapes 1-7 (Box 1086, Folder 14-20)
          - Tapes 8-13 (Box 1087, Folder 1-6)
        - Raw footage, miscellaneous, Umatic (Box 1087, Folder 7-14)
        - Raw footage, Salute to Volunteers Dinner, Umatic (12 tapes)
          - Tapes 1 to 6 (Box 1087, Folder 15-19)
          - Tapes 7-12 (Box 1088, Folder 1-8)
      - Sunday, 26 Jun
        - Raw footage, miscellaneous, Umatic (15 tapes) (Box 1088)
        - Tapes 1-12 (Box 1088, Folder 9-19)
        - Tapes 13-15 (Box 1089, Folder 1-4)
    - New Visual Identity for the YWCA of the USA, Umatic and VHS, Jun 1988, Aug 1988 * (Box 1089, Folder 5-6)
    - National Staff Retreat, Sep 1988
      - S.I.S.S.Y. with Stan Corfman, Umatic, Sep 1988 (Box 1089, Folder 7-8)
      - Groups' Structure/Function Presentations, Umatic, 15 Sep 1988 (Box 1089, Folder 9)
    - National Training, Canton Ohio, VHS, 1 Oct 1988 (Box 1089, Folder 10)
    - Location Footage [probably for "The YWCA Today-Celebrate A New"]
      - YWCA of Cincinnati, VHS, Oct 1988 (Box 1089, Folder 11)
      - YWCA of Japan Town, VHS, Oct 1988 (Box 1089, Folder 12)
      - YWCA of Sumter,VHS, Oct 1988 (Box 1089, Folder 13)
    - Y-Teens, Umatic, 22 Oct 1988 [possibly National Teen Assembly Jun 22?] (Box 1089, Folder 14-15)
    - National Board Meeting, Governance Training: John Carver/Group Reports, Umatic, 29 Oct 1988 (Box 1089, Folder 16)
    - Learning CenterXXII, Gwen Baker messages to, Umatic, 10 Nov 1988 (Box 1089, Folder 17)
    - Interview with Maxine Crump, Baton Rouge YWCA Board President, LDC, Umatic, 13 Nov 1988 (Box 1089, Folder 18)
    - "Crush," and "Lovesick," Teen discussion videos, VHS, 1989 * (Box 1089, Folder 19-20)
    - "YWCA Acting Out," [probably raw footage for "Crush" and "Lovesick," Umatic] 20 and 21 Jan 1989 (Box 1090, Folder 1)
    - "Faces In a Movement," Student YWCA, 1989, Umatic and VHS* (Box 1090, Folder 2-3)
    - Speak Out: Mid-Peninsula YWCA, CA, VHS, 1989 (Box 1090, Folder 4)
    - Tacoma YWCA Homeless School, segment in ABC News program "20/20," VHS, 20 Jan 1989 * (Box 1090, Folder 5)
    - "The YWCA Today: Celebrate A New...
      - 15 Feb 1989 version, Umatic (Box 1090, Folder 6)
      - 22 Jun 1989 revised edit, Umatic (Box 1090, Folder 7)
      - VHS, 1989 (Box 1090, Folder 8)
    - Convention Cycle I Meetings, 1989
      - Presentation video, '89: Black; Vision and Action; YWCA Today, VHS (Box 1090, Folder 9)
      - Glendora Putnam Speech, 19 Feb
        - Raw footage, Umatic (Box 1090, Folder 10)
        - Edited master, Umatic and VHS (Box 1090, Folder 11-12)
      - Workshop B, "Report Outs," raw footage, Umatic,16 Feb (Box 1090, Folder 13)
      - Reports, Edited master, Umatic, 26 Feb (Box 1090, Folder 14)
    - National Board Meeting, LDC, 19-21 May 1989
      - Panel Discussion, Umatic, 20 May (Box 1090, Folder 15-16)
      - Special Mission Panel, VHS (Box 1090, Folder 17)
    - Oral Histories conducted at National Board Meeting in Phoenix, VHS, May 1989
      - Elizabeth Marti, Ellen Dammond, and Betty Genné interviewed by Adrienne Jones, 19 May 1989* (Box 1090, Folder 18)
      - Beth L. Moore [Elisabeth Luce Moore] * (Box 1090, Folder 19)
      - Rosalie Oaks * (Box 1090, Folder 20)
      - Elizabeth Palmer * (Box 1090, Folder 21)
    - Association Review Training, "Tape I," Umatic, 19 May 1989 (Box 1090, Folder 22)
    - Retirement Fund, "Part II" [may be part of Association Review Training], Umatic, 19 May 1989 (Box 1091, Folder 1)
    - Speakers Bureau, VHS, May 1989
      - Skip Dockstader (Box 1091, Folder 2)
      - Lillian Kimura (Box 1091, Folder 3)
      - Tape 2 - VHS (Box 1091, Folder 4)
    - Mini Learning Center, training for new Executive Directors, Umatic, Jun 1989 (Box 1091, Folder 5)
    - Purpose Study Committee Panel presentation featuring Ellen Dammond, June Quan, Maguerita Medoza de Sugiyama, and Ann Stallard, distributed to all Community Associations, Jun 1989, Umatic (Box 1091, Folder 6)
    - Global Awareness Seminar/Workshop, 21-24 Jun 1989
      - Laurien Alexandre, Umatic, 21 Jun (Box 1091, Folder 7-9)
      - Seminar Reports, Umatic, 23 Jun (Box 1091, Folder 10)
      - Seminar Reports, Umatic, 24 Jun (Box 1091, Folder 11-12)
    - Purpose Study Committee meeting with Dame Nita Barrow as resource leader and presenter, Oct 1989, Umatic (Box 1091, Folder 13)
    - 30 second American Basketball Council Public Service Announcement with John Havlicek and Lynette Woodard referring to YWCA basketball programs, VHS, 3 Oct 1989 (Box 1091, Folder 14)
    - National Board Meeting at the Martin Luther King, Jr. Center for Nonviolent Change, VHS, 5 Nov 1989 * (Box 1091, Folder 15)
    - "Ten Stories Standing Tall," promotional video, YWCA of the City of New York, VHS, 12 Dec 1989 * (Box 1091, Folder 16)
    - Institute for Public Leadership, 1989-90
      - Edited master, Umatic (Box 1091, Folder 17)
      - [Public speaking] Practice Session, VHS (Box 1091, Folder 18)
      - Speeches of all participants, Umatic and VHS, 30 Nov 1990? (Box 1092, Folder 1-2)
    - "A Current Affair," Fox TV newsmagazine, story: "X-Rated at the Y" re production of pornographic movies in the YWCA of Los Angeles building, VHS, 1990 (Box 1092, Folder 3)
    - Education for 21st Century Citizenship: A Convergence of Agendas, Cambridge College panel including Gwen Baker, VHS, 1990 (Box 1092, Folder 4)
    - "Power of Vision," Charthouse Learning Corporation Discovering the Future Series re positive visions of the future, YWCA of the USA registration # 85167, 1990, VHS * (Box 1092, Folder 5)
    - WNBC News Forum, Gabe Pressman interview with Gwendolyn Baker, VHS, 1990 (Box 1092, Folder 6)
    - "Julia Morgan: Life by Design," commercially produced television documentary, VHS, 1990 (Box 1092, Folder 7)
    - 2 Public Service Announcements: "YWCA: Homeless #2" and "YWCA: Child Care #2," Umatic, 1990 (Box 1092, Folder 8-9)
    - Racial Justice Convocation, "Toward a Racial Justice Agenda for the 21st Century," 2-4 Feb 1990
      - Raw footage of luncheon, Umatic (Box 1092, Folder 10)
      - News clip, KPHO-TV 5, Phoenix, VHS, 3 Feb * (Box 1092, Folder 11)
      - Edited Master # 2 (Box 1092, Folder 12)
      - Speakers (Tape 2): C.T. Vivian, Dolores Huerta, Wilma Mankiller, Lloyd Davis (Rev. Stewart), VHS (Box 1092, Folder 13)
      - Highlights, Umatic and VHS * (Box 1092, Folder 14-15)
    - Speakers Bureau,27 Feb 1990 - VHS
      - Master, VHS (Box 1092, Folder 16)
      - All speeches from edited master, VHS (Box 1092, Folder 17)
      - Selected speeches, VHS (Box 1092, Folder 18)
    - Convention Mid-Triennium Conference, Orlando, 2-3 Mar 1990
      - Tapes #1-#5, Umatic (Box 1092, Folder 19-23)
      - Ann Stallard, Umatic and VHS (Box 1093, Folder 1-2)
      - Betty Genné, VHS (Box 1093, Folder 3)
      - Glendora Putnam, Umatic and VHS (Box 1093, Folder 4-5)
      - Gwendolyn Baker, Umatic and VHS (Box 1093, Folder 6-6a)
      - Panel Discussion, Edited, Umatic (Box 1093, Folder 7)
      - Panel Discussion re Purpose with Margarita de Sugiyama, Maia Bellon, and Pepper Schwartz, Umatic and VHS (Box 1093, Folder 8-8a)
    - Learning Center XXIII, Messages from Gwen Baker, Umatic, Jun 1990 (Box 1093, Folder 9)
    - "The Purpose Study Session" with Marilyn Whaley Winters, Chair, Committee to Study the Purpose, for use in local discussion sessions
      - Edited version, Umatic and VHS, 30 Jun 1990 * (Box 1093, Folder 10-11)
      - Marilyn Winters studio footage, Umatic (Box 1093, Folder 12)
    - Swearing in of Gwendolyn Baker as NY City School Board President (?), VHS, 31 Jul 1990 * (Box 1093, Folder 13)
    - Tiempo, New York City Channel 7 TV two part special report on the change of guard on the NY City School Board, with Gwendolyn Baker, VHS, 23 Jul and 9 Aug 1990, VHS (Box 1093, Folder 14-15)
    - "The Mother's Manual," YWCA of the USA Mother's Center, Beta and VHS, Sep 1990 (Box 1093, Folder 16-17)
    - "The Beacon," Brooklyn School District #18 program hosted by Dr. Harvey Gunn. Discussion of important issues in education today with Gwendolyn Baker in her capacity as NY City School Board President, VHS, also Learning Tech Fair XI 1st Place Winner, 1991* (Box 1093, Folder 18)
    - "By Faith: Christian Students Among the Cloud of Witnesses," documentary history of Christian student activism, used YWCA sources. Copyright Friendship Press, VHS, 1991 * (Box 1093, Folder 19)
    - Public Service Announcements from 1983, 1988, 1990, 1991, VHS (Box 1093, Folder 20)
    - "Redress: The JACL Campaign for Justice," part 1 and 2, Japanese American Citizens League, 1991VHS (Box 1093, Folder 21-22)
    - "Faces of Racism," Office of Racial Justice, Feb 1991 VHS (Box 1093, Folder 23)
    - Convention Preparation Meeting, 1 Feb 1991
      - Part I, A.M. portion, Umatic (Box 1094, Folder 1)
      - Part II, P.M. portion, Umatic (Box 1094, Folder 2)
      - LDC promo (tour of rooms set to music), Umatic (Box 1094, Folder 3)
      - VHS (Box 1094, Folder 4)
    - "YWCA Women of Achievement," Ohio YWCA, VHS, 8 Mar 1991 (Box 1094, Folder 5)
    - Elisabeth Luce Moore interview by marketing firm, 15 Mar 1991 (Box 1094, Folder 6)
    - Governor's Office for Children, 17-18 Apr 1991
      - Dr. Goodman, Umatic (Box 1094, Folder 7-8)
      - Judge Adams, Umatic (Box 1094, Folder 9-11)
    - 32nd National Convention (Atlanta15-19 May 1991)
      - Glendora Putnam Speech Excerpts, UCA 20s and VHS (Box 1094, Folder 12-13)
      - Sylvia Unzueta, VHS * (Box 1094, Folder 14)
      - Ann Stallard Acceptance Speech, VHS * (Box 1094, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous shots of Ann Stallard including part of acceptance speech, MBR 20s (Box 1094, Folder 16)
      - Stewardship Report, Umatic (Box 1094, Folder 17)
      - Audio for Stewardship Report, Umatic, 3 May 1991 (Box 1094, Folder 18)
      - Convention 1991 Recap, produced Nov 1992, Umatic (Box 1094, Folder 19)
    - "Join Us," 30 second Public Service Announcement, Phyllis Kerle Associates, Umatic and VHS, 24 Jun 1991 * (Box 1095, Folder 1-2)
    - Uganda Study-Travel Program, 22 Jun-5 Jul 1991
      - "Nineteen Incredible Days," produced? Oct 1991, MBU 18s and VHS (Box 1095, Folder 3-4)
      - Raw footage, Umatic (Box 1095, Folder 5-9)
    - A Fact Finding Experience: El SalvadorJul 1991 - VHS (Box 1095, Folder 10)
    - World Council, 25 Jul-3 Aug 1991
      - Ann Nichols, on Singapore, UCA 20s (Box 1095, Folder 11)
      - Original footage, Ann Nichols, UCA 20s (Box 1095, Folder 12)
      - World Council with Ann Nichols, VHS (Box 1095, Folder 13)
      - World Council 1991: Women Together Making a Difference, MBR 20s and VHS (Box 1095, Folder 14-15)
      - Preliminary World Council Photo Edit, Norway, 1991, produced Sep 1991, MBR 60 and VHS (Box 1095, Folder 16-17)
    - "It's a Hit!" YWCA of the USA and US Field Hockey Association, promotional video about field hockey, VHS, Sept 1991* (Box 1095, Folder 18)
    - EEOC v. YWCA, historical review of issues narrated by Glendora Putnam, 16 Sep 1991, VHS (Box 1095, Folder 19)
    - Congressional Families Action for Breast Cancer Awareness Program (YWCA of the USA a Program Partner) Press Conference and Seminar at Columbia Hospital, Washington, DC, Oct 1991, VHS (Box 1095, Folder 20)
    - China Trip to celebrate YWCA of China's 101st anniversary, footage from 8mm film, Oct 1991, Umatic (Box 1096, Folder 1-4)
    - Learning Center XXV
      - Ecumenical Service--Lillian Kimura, Anne Stallard, Japanese visitor; Oct/Nov 1991 - VHS (Box 1096, Folder 5)
      - Silver Anniversary Dinner glimpses: Dr. Baker, Ann Stallard, dancing, toasts, diningOct/Nov 1991 - VHS (Box 1096, Folder 6)
      - Learning Center, Halloween Carnival, 31 Oct 1991 - VHS (Box 1096, Folder 7)
    - Chrysler Corporation television series "Rediscover America" spot #23 featuring Gwendolyn Calvert Baker, circa 1992, VHS (Box 1096, Folder 8)
    - "Give It a Shot!," National Girls Tennis Program promotional video, 1992, VHS * (Box 1096, Folder 9)
    - EEOC v. YWCA of Tucson and YWCA of the U.S.A.
      - Discussion of the litigation, possibly Chris Carty? for a National Board meeting?, VHS, circa 1992 (Box 1096, Folder 10)
      - Presentation by Chris Carty and Glendora Putnam distributed to Community Associations with information about the consent decree, 1992, VHS * (Box 1096, Folder 11)
      - Chris Carty raw footage, taped 10 Jan 1992, Umatic (Box 1096, Folder 12-14)
      - EEOC Studio Shoot raw footage, Gwen Baker, Mercedes Marquez, Glendora Putnam, Ann Stallard, circa 1992, VHS (Box 1096, Folder 14a)
    - Convention Cycle I Meeting, 20-22 Mar 1992
      - Raw footage, tapes 4, 6, 7, Phoenix, AZ, Umatic (Box 1096, Folder 15-17)
      - Ann Stallard Speech, 22 Mar, Umatic and VHS (Box 1096, Folder 18-19)
      - Gwendolyn Baker, Status of the YWCA, 20 Mar 1992 - Umatic (Box 1096, Folder 20)
    - Visit of China YWCA leaders to U.S., Apr-May 1992
      - Summit on Women's Issues in the USA and China, 16 May 1992, VHS (Box 1097, Folder 1-2)
      - Raw footage: photo stills transfer and narration, 29 Apr 1992, Umatic (Box 1097, Folder 3)
      - Raw footage: Music, May 1992, Beta (Box 1097, Folder 4)
    - National Board Meeting, 15 May 1992
      - Raw footage, Camera 1, Umatic (Box 1097, Folder 5-7)
      - Raw footage, Camera 2, Umatic (Box 1097, Folder 8-10)
    - Project Redesign, presentation for National Board meeting, 15 May 1992
      - Raw footage, Umatic (Box 1097, Folder 11-13)
      - Edited version, with update by Ann Stallard, Umatic and VHS* (Box 1097, Folder 14-15)
      - Ann Stallard, Studio footage for update, Umatic, 17 May 1992 (Box 1097, Folder 16)
    - All Staff Meeting "Inspirational Opening," MBR 20s and VHS, Sep 1992 (Box 1097, Folder 17-18)
    - Project Redesign, reports with Gwen Baker and consultant, dubbing master on Beta for duplication to VHS, Nov 1992 (Box 1098, Folder 1-2)
    - "The Breast Care Test," copyright Avon Products, Inc., in English and Spanish, 1993, VHS (Box 1098, Folder 3-4)
    - ENCOREplus Promotional video produced by Zimmerman/Edelson Inc., 1993, VHS (Box 1098, Folder 5)
    - YWCA of Tucson 75th Anniversary video, Mar 1993, VHS (Box 1098, Folder 6)